<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://komga.org/blog</id>
    <title>Announcements</title>
    <updated>2023-12-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://komga.org/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Latest Komga announcements</subtitle>
    <icon>https://komga.org/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[eBook drop 2]]></title>
        <id>https://komga.org/blog/ebook-drop2</id>
        <link href="https://komga.org/blog/ebook-drop2"/>
        <updated>2023-12-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Version 1.9.0 contains the second feature drop for Ebooks support.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Version <a href="https://github.com/gotson/komga/releases/tag/1.9.0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">1.9.0</a> contains the second feature drop for Ebooks support.</p><p>It brings nice additions to the initial release, most notably the read progress will be kept when reading and restored, same as with other books.</p><p>The analysis process of EPUB files was also revamped, and some EPUB files that were not analyzed before should be working fine now.</p><p>While the first release forced all the EPUB files through the Epub Reader, this release brings back compatibility with the Divina Reader for pre-paginated EPUB files containing only images. This also restores support for the Pages API, and thus the compatibility with Tachiyomi, or any OPDS-PSE client.</p><p>Head over to the <a href="https://github.com/gotson/komga/releases/tag/1.9.0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Release Notes</a> for more details on all the new features and fixes.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>gotson</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/gotson</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="upgrade" term="upgrade"/>
        <category label="komga" term="komga"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[eBook support]]></title>
        <id>https://komga.org/blog/ebook-support</id>
        <link href="https://komga.org/blog/ebook-support"/>
        <updated>2023-11-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Version 1.8.0 is bringing a long awaited feature: proper eBook support!]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Version <a href="https://github.com/gotson/komga/releases/tag/1.8.0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">1.8.0</a> is bringing a long awaited feature: <strong>proper eBook support!</strong></p><p>Github issue <a href="https://github.com/gotson/komga/issues/221" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#221</a> has been opened for more than 3 years, and has finally been tackled.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-you-need-to-know">What you need to know<a href="#what-you-need-to-know" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What you need to know" title="Direct link to What you need to know">​</a></h2><ul><li>eBooks behave like any other book in Komga, in regards to series or metadata. You can even mix comic books and ebooks in the same series.</li><li>only EPUB format is supported. Other formats will not be supported in the future.</li><li>existing EPUB files will be re-analyzed. If you had image-only EPUB, those may not be compatible anymore with third-party clients.</li><li>the web EPUB reader is a very first version, and <strong>does not support saving progress</strong>. Read progress saving and restore will come in a future release.</li><li>any book in Komga can be read with <a href="https://readium.org/webpub-manifest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">WebPub</a> compatible clients.</li><li><strong>There will be issues</strong>. EPUB is a complex format, and many EPUB files are not properly built. Raise issues <a href="https://github.com/gotson/komga/issues/new/choose" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">on Github</a> for support.</li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="other-recent-changes-you-may-have-missed">Other recent changes you may have missed<a href="#other-recent-changes-you-may-have-missed" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Other recent changes you may have missed" title="Direct link to Other recent changes you may have missed">​</a></h2><p>In case you haven't kept up with the release notes since version 1.0.0, here are the most significant changes:</p><ul><li>Komga is now available as a <a href="/docs/installation/desktop">desktop app</a>, and is available in the <a href="/docs/installation/ms-store">Microsoft Store</a></li><li>Multiple settings are now configurable from the <a href="/docs/guides/server-settings">Server Settings</a> screen. You may need to cleanup your configuration file and remove deprecated entries.</li><li>Thumbnails size can now be configured in Server Settings.</li><li>Background task management has been revamped, and now supports proper parallel executions (configurable in Server Settings).</li><li>Komga now has support for <a href="/docs/guides/oneshots">One-Shots</a>.</li><li>a <a href="/docs/guides/cli">Command Line Interface</a> was added to update forgotten password for the admin account.</li></ul>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>gotson</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/gotson</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="upgrade" term="upgrade"/>
        <category label="komga" term="komga"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prepare for v1.0.0]]></title>
        <id>https://komga.org/blog/prepare-v1</id>
        <link href="https://komga.org/blog/prepare-v1"/>
        <updated>2023-03-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The future v1.0.0 will bring some breaking changes, this guide will help you to prepare for the next major version.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The future v1.0.0 will bring some breaking changes, this guide will help you to prepare for the next major version.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="before-upgrading">Before upgrading<a href="#before-upgrading" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Before upgrading" title="Direct link to Before upgrading">​</a></h2><ul><li>If you run Docker, it is advisable to use the <code>0.x</code> tag instead of <code>latest</code>. You will be able to decide when you want to upgrade, especially if you are updating containers automatically.</li><li>Backup your <code>database.sqlite</code>. You can find it in the configuration directory, by default:<ul><li>on Windows: <code>%USERPROFILE%/.komga/database.sqlite</code></li><li>on Unix: <code>~/.komga/database.sqlite</code></li><li>on Docker: in the directory you mounted as <code>/config</code></li></ul></li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="breaking-changes">Breaking changes<a href="#breaking-changes" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Breaking changes" title="Direct link to Breaking changes">​</a></h2><ul><li>The minimum Java version required will be Java 17:<ul><li>If you run Komga using the <code>jar</code>, you will need to make sure your Java version is sufficient by running <code>java -version</code>.</li><li>If you run Komga using Docker, you don't need to do anything.</li></ul></li><li>The hashing algorithm for files and pages will change. Previous hashes for files and pages will be deleted. On startup, if hashing is enabled, Komga will re-hash files and pages using the new algorithm.</li><li>The default port will be changed from <code>8080</code> to <code>25600</code>:<ul><li>If you use Docker, you will need to update your container or compose configuration to expose the new port.</li><li>You may need to adjust your reverse proxy settings.</li><li>You can still change the port <a href="/docs/installation/configuration#server_port--serverport-port">through configuration</a>.</li></ul></li></ul>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>gotson</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/gotson</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="breaking change" term="breaking change"/>
        <category label="upgrade" term="upgrade"/>
        <category label="komga" term="komga"/>
    </entry>
</feed>